<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>psychological thriller on Backyard</title><link>/tags/psychological-thriller/</link><description>Recent content in psychological thriller on Backyard</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 11:40:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/psychological-thriller/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Beauty and Horror of 'Perfect Blue'</title><link>/post/movie-perfect-blue-1997/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 11:40:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-perfect-blue-1997/</guid><description>Introduction Perfect Blue is a psychological thriller anime, to put a label to it. At its heart, however, it is a piognant, suspenseful, ghastly, thought-provoking masterpiece that explores such delicate themes such as celebrity lifestyle, voyeurism, desire, obsession, online identity and be audacious enough to challenge denser themes as in dissocative identity disorder, mental health, nudity, rape. It is masterful in its ability to ask so many questions and leave the audience with a nagging longing for those questions to be answered.</description></item><item><title>Black Swan (2010)</title><link>/post/black-swan-2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/black-swan-2010/</guid><description>Central Theme Spoilers Ahead. Proceed at your discretion. The central theme of Black swan is the exploration of human nature. Following Blake Snyder Beat Sheet or BS2, there is a well defined central dilemma followed by an all-is-lost phase which gives rise to the fundamental transformation in the protagonist. The movie, more specifically, explores true passion for something and the ability to forego one&amp;rsquo;s identity for it.
My interpretation The movie follows Nina Sayers, a delicate ballerina who is the embodiment of perfection.</description></item></channel></rss>