<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>That Damn Blog</title><link>https://aikea.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on That Damn Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:00:32 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aikea.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Beauty and Horror of 'Perfect Blue'</title><link>https://aikea.github.io/movie-perfect-blue-1997/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 11:40:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aikea.github.io/movie-perfect-blue-1997/</guid><description>Introduction Perfect Blue is a psychological thriller anime, to put a label to it. At its heart, however, it is a piognant, suspenseful, ghastly, thought-provoking masterpiece that explores such delicate themes such as celebrity lifestyle, voyeurism, desire, obsession, online identity and be audacious enough to challenge denser themes as in dissocative identity disorder, mental health, nudity, rape. It is masterful in its ability to ask so many questions and leave the audience with a nagging longing for those questions to be answered.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://aikea.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:01:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aikea.github.io/about/</guid><description>What should you expect from this blog? This site is my journal. Expect rambling about my day-to-day business, my thoughts and interpretations of things and people around me.
I will be as true and raw as a teenager can possibly be. I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll take this as a sign of my maturity to acknowledge these issues rather than my sign of weakness.
Who am I? 🐹 Hi there!</description></item><item><title>Watchlog</title><link>https://aikea.github.io/watchlog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 17:58:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://aikea.github.io/watchlog/</guid><description>Ok, I admit my defeat! Inspite of promising myself that I would focus solely on college exam preparation and academics in general, I have given into my temptation and desire. (When I now introspect, I realize I have wasted a lot of time doing everything except academics.)
I am a big organization freak and turn insane easily if I find any part of my life going undocumented. (This is one of the primary motivations for this blog.</description></item><item><title>Black Swan (2010)</title><link>https://aikea.github.io/black-swan-2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aikea.github.io/black-swan-2010/</guid><description>Central Theme Spoilers Ahead. Proceed at your discretion. The central theme of Black swan is the exploration of human nature. Following Blake Snyder Beat Sheet or BS2, there is a well defined central dilemma followed by an all-is-lost phase which gives rise to the fundamental transformation in the protagonist. The movie, more specifically, explores true passion for something and the ability to forego one&amp;rsquo;s identity for it.
My interpretation The movie follows Nina Sayers, a delicate ballerina who is the embodiment of perfection.</description></item><item><title>Requiem For A Dream (2000)</title><link>https://aikea.github.io/requiem-for-a-dream-2000/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aikea.github.io/requiem-for-a-dream-2000/</guid><description>&lt;hr>
&lt;div class="sm col background-warning">
Spoilers ahead. Of course.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Horror movies generally occupy that grey area between paranormal and fantasy, fueled by imagination. But what if you can bring out the horror in the reality we live in? That is what Darren Aronofsky&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Requiem for a Dream&amp;rdquo; is about and more.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>