<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thoughts on Vocal Cords</title><link>/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in thoughts on Vocal Cords</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 10:08:33 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The joy of 'Back to the Future'</title><link>/post/movie-bttf-1985/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 10:08:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-bttf-1985/</guid><description>Ah, those good ol 80s time. When everything was simple and sweet. Story-writers wrote simple stories, with simple dialogues and simple action, when the sheer simplicity of the characters made them memorable. How one started with a premise, built it to a conflict and then marvellously resolved it.
Movie Poster for BTTF, 1985
Robert Zemeckis&amp;rsquo; Back to the Future is a child of that era. A coherent, brilliantly executed script where every events seems to fall in place in harmony with others.</description></item><item><title>Normal People: The complex terrain of modern relationships</title><link>/post/series-normal-people-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 19:24:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/series-normal-people-2020/</guid><description>Disclaimer: This is mostly a brain dump of how much I liked this series. So, if you are interested in me raving and blabbering about it, not to mention the generous spoilers, don&amp;rsquo;t read this. Also, it&amp;rsquo;s not one of my finest works. I just wanted to record everything I observed.
Introduction Normal People is a 2020 12-episode romance web series based on a book by Sally Rooney produced by Hulu and BBC.</description></item><item><title>Titanic – A study in human psychology</title><link>/post/movie-titanic-1997/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 09:29:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-titanic-1997/</guid><description>Titanic is a story of two lovers, a study in human psychology, a smack down on the aristocratic bourgeois, an tantalizing crush on the pride of human marvels, and of course a tragic history retold - all in dramatic, enrapturing and brilliant cinematography.
Dread. Cameron&amp;rsquo;s Titanic is full of sarcastic iconic shots.
Story of two lovers I remember the night I first saw Titanic, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the image of Rose out of my head.</description></item><item><title>'The Little Death' is more than just a sexual comedy</title><link>/post/movie-the-little-death-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 13:25:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-the-little-death-2014/</guid><description>CAUTION: Explicit post. Maybe spoilers. Proceed at your discretion.
Introduction &amp;lsquo;The Little Death&amp;rsquo; is a 2014 Australian featurette running for ~90 minutes which classifies as a sexual comedy. It traces the lives of five urban couples who are engaged in exotic fetishes apart from normal sex. It explores the effects of an individuals&amp;rsquo; desires on their marriage, daily life, emotional tolerance and other facets of life.
The phrase &amp;lsquo;The Little Death&amp;rsquo; (fr.</description></item><item><title>The Beauty and Horror of 'Perfect Blue'</title><link>/post/movie-perfect-blue-1997/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 11:40:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-perfect-blue-1997/</guid><description>Introduction Perfect Blue is a psychological thriller anime, to put a label to it. At its heart, however, it is a piognant, suspenseful, ghastly, thought-provoking masterpiece that explores such delicate themes such as celebrity lifestyle, voyeurism, desire, obsession, online identity and be audacious enough to challenge denser themes as in dissocative identity disorder, mental health, nudity, rape. It is masterful in its ability to ask so many questions and leave the audience with a nagging longing for those questions to be answered.</description></item></channel></rss>