<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Vocal Cords</title><link>/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Vocal Cords</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 17:54:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>"A Clockwork Orange" is Kubrick's realisation of an Orwellian fantasy</title><link>/post/movie-a-clockwork-orange-1971/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 17:54:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-a-clockwork-orange-1971/</guid><description>Alex DeLarge in Stanley Kubrick&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;A Clockwork Orange&amp;rsquo;, 1971
Stanley Kubrick&amp;rsquo;s A Clockwork Orange tries to be many things in a nifty way. A satire on state control, a study of the effervescent youth, and an outlandish extol of the Ninth Symphony. Set in Britain, Orange is an English film using a made-up vocabulary derived from Russian that is delightful to listen to. With sentences such as: &amp;ldquo;Come and get one in the yarbles if you have any yarbles you eunuch jelly, thou&amp;rdquo;, and words like &amp;ldquo;malenky&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;rassoodocks&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;devotchka&amp;rdquo;, one would want to simply keep listening to it.</description></item><item><title>Psycho: An investigation of evil and malice</title><link>/post/movie-psycho-1960/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 17:58:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-psycho-1960/</guid><description>Psycho, Alfred Hithcock, 1960
&amp;ldquo;We all go a little mad sometimes&amp;rdquo;, notes Norman Bates (Anthony Perkins), the lonely owner of Bates Motel, a secluded motel off the highway and the unfateful place where Marion Crane (Janet Leigh) decides to spend the night while on the run after stealing $40,000 from her boss. I think this dialogue summarizes Psycho, Alfred Hitchcock&amp;rsquo;s seminal 1960 work investigating the human tendency to bend towards evil and malice.</description></item><item><title>The French Dispatch: An absurdist eye-candy</title><link>/post/the-french-dispatch-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 17:28:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/the-french-dispatch-2021/</guid><description>The French Dispatch, 2021 - Wes Anderson
Wes Anderson is a director whose works when subjected to multiple watching will be rewarding for the audience. Simply because of the sheer amount of information in each scene and shot. Stories that verge on the border of absurdity, most often comical, and seldom dark, coupled with an expansive mise-en-scene and a most peculiar camera style, Wes Anderson has created for himself a very distinctive style, one that is truly his own.</description></item><item><title>Playtime: A satire on corporates and capitalism</title><link>/post/movie-playtime-1967/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 14:54:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-playtime-1967/</guid><description>Playtime (1967) - Jacques Tati
Playtime is unlike any other movie I have seen. It manages to be a quirky, slapstick-esque, satirical tale of a modern technological urban Paris. It follows a retired army man, Mr. Hulot (Jacques Tati) who, befuddled by perfect matchbox office skyscrapers and machine-controlled offices, eventually gets lost and ends up in a premium restaurant. There is a subplot running parallel with it that follows Ms.</description></item><item><title>The joy of 'Back to the Future'</title><link>/post/movie-bttf-1985/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 10:08:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-bttf-1985/</guid><description>Ah, those good ol 80s time. When everything was simple and sweet. Story-writers wrote simple stories, with simple dialogues and simple action, when the sheer simplicity of the characters made them memorable. How one started with a premise, built it to a conflict and then marvellously resolved it.
Movie Poster for BTTF, 1985
Robert Zemeckis&amp;rsquo; Back to the Future is a child of that era. A coherent, brilliantly executed script where every events seems to fall in place in harmony with others.</description></item><item><title>Normal People: The complex terrain of modern relationships</title><link>/post/series-normal-people-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 19:24:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/series-normal-people-2020/</guid><description>Disclaimer: This is mostly a brain dump of how much I liked this series. So, if you are interested in me raving and blabbering about it, not to mention the generous spoilers, don&amp;rsquo;t read this. Also, it&amp;rsquo;s not one of my finest works. I just wanted to record everything I observed.
Introduction Normal People is a 2020 12-episode romance web series based on a book by Sally Rooney produced by Hulu and BBC.</description></item><item><title>Titanic – A study in human psychology</title><link>/post/movie-titanic-1997/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 09:29:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-titanic-1997/</guid><description>Titanic is a story of two lovers, a study in human psychology, a smack down on the aristocratic bourgeois, an tantalizing crush on the pride of human marvels, and of course a tragic history retold - all in dramatic, enrapturing and brilliant cinematography.
Dread. Cameron&amp;rsquo;s Titanic is full of sarcastic iconic shots.
Story of two lovers I remember the night I first saw Titanic, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the image of Rose out of my head.</description></item><item><title>Who is the real 'heinous bitch' in this Shakespearean adaptation?</title><link>/post/movie-10tihay-1999/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 06:13:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-10tihay-1999/</guid><description>Movie poster of 10TIHAY featuring Heath Ledger and Julia Stiles
In an unapologetic hustle to combat monotonicity, I ended up rewatching &amp;ldquo;10 Things I Hate About You&amp;rdquo; yesternight. The rather cocky title that crowns this post was a question that sprung to my mind during that watch. I think someone said it right when they said you don&amp;rsquo;t really watch a movie the first time because your brain is all so involved in processing the actions, dialogues, props, making sense of the storyline and generally answering the question, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s it about?</description></item><item><title>'The Little Death' is more than just a sexual comedy</title><link>/post/movie-the-little-death-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 13:25:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-the-little-death-2014/</guid><description>CAUTION: Explicit post. Maybe spoilers. Proceed at your discretion.
Introduction &amp;lsquo;The Little Death&amp;rsquo; is a 2014 Australian featurette running for ~90 minutes which classifies as a sexual comedy. It traces the lives of five urban couples who are engaged in exotic fetishes apart from normal sex. It explores the effects of an individuals&amp;rsquo; desires on their marriage, daily life, emotional tolerance and other facets of life.
The phrase &amp;lsquo;The Little Death&amp;rsquo; (fr.</description></item><item><title>How 'Dazed and Confused' captures the gore and glory of being a teenager</title><link>/post/movie-dazed-and-confused-1993/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 08:31:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-dazed-and-confused-1993/</guid><description>Introduction From left: Don, Wooderson, Pink and Mitchie in Dazed and Confused, 1993
Tom Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s familiar bass notes kick in, followed by Steven Tyler&amp;rsquo;s chorus of &amp;lsquo;Sweeeet Emooootion&amp;rsquo;. A montage of high school students, smoking, chatting casually. And then, it is declared in bold,
&amp;ldquo;The last day of school, May 28 1976, 1:05 pm&amp;rdquo;.
The protagonists, a web of school friends, are introduced, all caught up in their own worlds.</description></item><item><title>The Beauty and Horror of 'Perfect Blue'</title><link>/post/movie-perfect-blue-1997/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 11:40:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-perfect-blue-1997/</guid><description>Introduction Perfect Blue is a psychological thriller anime, to put a label to it. At its heart, however, it is a piognant, suspenseful, ghastly, thought-provoking masterpiece that explores such delicate themes such as celebrity lifestyle, voyeurism, desire, obsession, online identity and be audacious enough to challenge denser themes as in dissocative identity disorder, mental health, nudity, rape. It is masterful in its ability to ask so many questions and leave the audience with a nagging longing for those questions to be answered.</description></item><item><title>Black Swan (2010)</title><link>/post/black-swan-2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/black-swan-2010/</guid><description>Central Theme Spoilers Ahead. Proceed at your discretion. The central theme of Black swan is the exploration of human nature. Following Blake Snyder Beat Sheet or BS2, there is a well defined central dilemma followed by an all-is-lost phase which gives rise to the fundamental transformation in the protagonist. The movie, more specifically, explores true passion for something and the ability to forego one&amp;rsquo;s identity for it.
My interpretation The movie follows Nina Sayers, a delicate ballerina who is the embodiment of perfection.</description></item><item><title>Why 'Requiem For A Dream' is a melancholic masterpiece</title><link>/post/requiem-for-a-dream-2000/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/requiem-for-a-dream-2000/</guid><description>&lt;div class="sm col background-warning">
Spoilers ahead. Of course.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Horror movies generally occupy that grey area between paranormal and fantasy, fueled by imagination. But what if you can bring out the horror in the reality we live in? That is what Darren Aronofsky&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Requiem for a Dream&amp;rdquo; is about and more.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>