<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Backyard</title><link>/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Backyard</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 09:29:04 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Titanic – A study in human psychology</title><link>/post/movie-titanic-1997/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 09:29:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-titanic-1997/</guid><description>NOTE: This is an early draft version. Images and possible further editing are expected soon.
Titanic is a story of two lovers, a study in human psychology, a smack down on the aristocratic bourgeois, an tantalizing crush on the pride of human marvels, and of course a tragic history retold - all in dramatic, enrapturing and brilliant cinematography.
Story of two lovers I remember the night I first saw Titanic, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the image of Rose out of my head.</description></item><item><title>Who is the real 'heinous bitch' in this Shakespearean adaptation?</title><link>/post/movie-10tihay-1999/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 06:13:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-10tihay-1999/</guid><description>Movie poster of 10TIHAY featuring Heath Ledger and Julia Stiles
In an unapologetic hustle to combat monotonicity, I ended up rewatching &amp;ldquo;10 Things I Hate About You&amp;rdquo; yesternight. The rather cocky title that crowns this post was a question that sprung to my mind during that watch. I think someone said it right when they said you don&amp;rsquo;t really watch a movie the first time because your brain is all so involved in processing the actions, dialogues, props, making sense of the storyline and generally answering the question, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s it about?</description></item><item><title>'The Little Death' is more than just a sexual comedy</title><link>/post/movie-the-little-death-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 13:25:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-the-little-death-2014/</guid><description>CAUTION: Explicit post. Maybe spoilers. Proceed at your discretion.
Introduction &amp;lsquo;The Little Death&amp;rsquo; is a 2014 Australian featurette running for ~90 minutes which classifies as a sexual comedy. It traces the lives of five urban couples who are engaged in exotic fetishes apart from normal sex. It explores the effects of an individuals' desires on their marriage, daily life, emotional tolerance and other facets of life.
The phrase &amp;lsquo;The Little Death&amp;rsquo; (fr.</description></item><item><title>How 'Dazed and Confused' captures the gore and glory of being a teenager</title><link>/post/movie-dazed-and-confused-1993/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 08:31:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-dazed-and-confused-1993/</guid><description>Introduction From left: Don, Wooderson, Pink and Mitchie in Dazed and Confused, 1993
Tom Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s familiar bass notes kick in, followed by Steven Tyler&amp;rsquo;s chorus of &amp;lsquo;Sweeeet Emooootion&amp;rsquo;. A montage of high school students, smoking, chatting casually. And then, it is declared in bold,
&amp;ldquo;The last day of school, May 28 1976, 1:05 pm&amp;rdquo;.
The protagonists, a web of school friends, are introduced, all caught up in their own worlds.</description></item><item><title>The Beauty and Horror of 'Perfect Blue'</title><link>/post/movie-perfect-blue-1997/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 11:40:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/movie-perfect-blue-1997/</guid><description>Introduction Perfect Blue is a psychological thriller anime, to put a label to it. At its heart, however, it is a piognant, suspenseful, ghastly, thought-provoking masterpiece that explores such delicate themes such as celebrity lifestyle, voyeurism, desire, obsession, online identity and be audacious enough to challenge denser themes as in dissocative identity disorder, mental health, nudity, rape. It is masterful in its ability to ask so many questions and leave the audience with a nagging longing for those questions to be answered.</description></item><item><title>Black Swan (2010)</title><link>/post/black-swan-2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/black-swan-2010/</guid><description>Central Theme Spoilers Ahead. Proceed at your discretion. The central theme of Black swan is the exploration of human nature. Following Blake Snyder Beat Sheet or BS2, there is a well defined central dilemma followed by an all-is-lost phase which gives rise to the fundamental transformation in the protagonist. The movie, more specifically, explores true passion for something and the ability to forego one&amp;rsquo;s identity for it.
My interpretation The movie follows Nina Sayers, a delicate ballerina who is the embodiment of perfection.</description></item><item><title>Why 'Requiem For A Dream' is a melancholic masterpiece</title><link>/post/requiem-for-a-dream-2000/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/requiem-for-a-dream-2000/</guid><description>&lt;div class="sm col background-warning">
Spoilers ahead. Of course.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Horror movies generally occupy that grey area between paranormal and fantasy, fueled by imagination. But what if you can bring out the horror in the reality we live in? That is what Darren Aronofsky&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Requiem for a Dream&amp;rdquo; is about and more.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>